The best two-hour vacation in town!
California Suite is a comedy, drama, romance film directed by Herbert Ross.
The misadventures of four groups of guests at the Beverly Hills Hotel.
Hannah Warren, played by Jane Fonda.
Bill Warren, played by Alan Alda.
Diana Barrie, played by Maggie Smith.
Sidney Cochran, played by Michael Caine.
Marvin Michaels, played by Walter Matthau.
Millie Michaels, played by Elaine May.
California Suite is a 1978 American anthology
comedy film directed by Herbert Ross.
The screenplay by Neil Simon is based on his 1976 play.
Similar in format to Simon's earlier work Plaza Suite, the film follows four
separate stories involving guests staying in a suite in a luxury hotel.
The film stars Alan Alda, Michael Caine, Bill Cosby, Jane Fonda, Walter
Matthau, Elaine May, Richard Pryor and Maggie Smith.
The movie was released in December 1978, and received mixed reviews.
It received three Academy Award nominations, including Best Adapted Screenplay
for Simon, with Maggie Smith winning Best Supporting Actress.
Smith also won the Golden Globe Award for Best Actress in a Motion Picture – Musical or
Comedy, and the film was nominated for Best Motion Picture – Musical or Comedy.
The film explores themes of hotel, husband wife relationship, based on
play or musical, beverly hills, multiple storylines.
The tone is lighthearted and emotional.